so let's speak a little bit about how
所以让我们谈谈如何
hard is it to compute a Nash equilibrium
很难计算纳什均衡
in a normal phone game this is an
在正常的电话游戏中，这是
involved topic and I'll just give you a
涉及的话题，我给你一个
taste for it let me draw your attention
尝起来让我引起你的注意
to two specific algorithms for computing
两种特定的计算算法
a sample natural equilibrium and again
样本自然平衡
these are two out of a long line of
这是一长串的两个
algorithms that have been investigated
已经研究过的算法
and these are a sort of two extreme the
这是两个极端
one of them starts with a mathematical
其中之一以数学开始
formulation of the problem called a
问题的表达称为
linear complementarity problem and you
线性互补问题和你
want to set it up as a mathematical
想要将其设置为数学
optimization problem you can apply
您可以应用的优化问题
various algorithms to that and the most
最重要的各种算法
famous one for two players games is due
著名的两人游戏之一
to Lemke and houses and this is an
到伦克和房屋，这是一个
algorithm that really displays a deep
真正展现出深刻的算法
understanding of the mathematical
对数学的理解
structure of what a game is and the
游戏的结构以及
nature of Nash equilibria on perhaps the
纳什均衡的性质也许
other extreme is what is called the
另一个极端是所谓的
support enumeration method a recent
支持枚举方法最近
procedure that doesn't have as deep and
没有那么深和
insight into the structure of the
洞察结构
problem it says simply the following it
问题，它说只需跟随它
says if you fix the support of the
说如果你修复的支持
strategies of the player and the support
玩家的策略和支持
of the strategy players are those
战略参与者中的那些是
actions are played with nonzero
动作以非零播放
probability if you fix that support then
如果您修复该支持的可能性
the problem becomes very easy you can
问题变得非常容易，您可以
set it up as a linear program and solve
将其设置为线性程序并求解
it efficiently and that will be the end
它有效，这将是结局
of it if it weren't for the case that
如果不是这样的话
there that indeed there are an
那里确实有一个
exponential number of supports to
支持的指数数量
explore and so the trick in this
探索，所以这个技巧
procedure is to explore them cleverly
程序是巧妙地探索它们
using Clarrie eristic s-- and that's
使用Clarrie eristic s--
called the support enumeration there's a
称为支持枚举
clever heuristic work for
巧妙的启发式工作
how to enumerate those supports and
如何列举这些支持，以及
check them one by one although the
尽管他们一一检查
latter procedure is not as smart or as
后面的过程不那么聪明
insightful as the Lemke housen I turns
当我转身成为Lemke屋子时很有见地
out that in practice it tends to run
在实践中它倾向于运行
very fast so we've seen the algorithm
非常快，所以我们已经看过算法
people have tried very hard to find
人们努力寻找
algorithms computing a sample Nash
计算样本Nash的算法
equilibrium
平衡
and it does seem hard the question is
问题似乎确实很难
can we somehow capture that formally
我们可以以某种方式正式捕获它吗
within the complexity hierarchy and and
在复杂性层次结构中，以及
and for that we need to introduce some
为此，我们需要介绍一些
you know new new concepts the essential
你知道新概念必不可少
concept is that of the new class of
概念是新类别的
problems called P P ad for polynomial
多项式的PP ad问题
parity arguments directed graph
奇偶参数有向图
introduced by christos papadimitriou in
由克里斯托斯·帕帕迪米特里乌（Christos papadimitriou）在
1994 we won't go into detail but just so
1994年，我们不再赘述，只是如此
you know the chronology P P ad is a
您知道时间顺序PP广告是
specialization of a class called TF NP
TF NP类的专业化
which is in turn with a specialization
反过来又有专长
of a problem called f NP a going detail
f NP问题的细节
here is is beyond the scope of what we
这超出了我们的范围
want to speak about but it does help us
想谈一谈，但这确实对我们有帮助
now position the complexity of finding a
现在定位找到一个
sample Nash equilibrium in the
样本中的纳什均衡
complexity hierarchy and again we have
复杂性层次结构
the class of polynomial time problems of
多项式时间问题的类别
problem that can be verified in
可以验证的问题
polynomial time with these being the
多项式时间，这些是
hardest among them and given that P PAE
其中最难的是P PAE
turns out to reside somewhere within
原来是住在里面的某个地方
this class now again we don't know
再次上这堂课，我们不知道
whether this entire class did not
整个班级都没有
collapse and all become one of the same
崩溃，都成为同一个
it's why do you believe that it does not
这就是为什么您认为它不会
but proof doesn't exist however we do
但是我们不存在证明
know that P P 80 lies someplace in
知道PP 80位于
between P and
在P和
now what does that have to do with the
现在这与
problem computing a Nash equilibrium
计算纳什均衡的问题
well that's where the the following
嗯，这是以下内容
theorems come in originally it was shown
定理最初来自它表明
that the problem of computing a Nash
计算纳什的问题
equilibrium is complete for this class
该课程的均衡是完全的
pped
that is it's the hardest among all
那是最困难的
problem that class initially proved for
班级最初证明的问题
four players then for all four games
然后四场比赛的四名球员
with three or more players and then
三个或更多玩家，然后
finally in oh six for all class of games
最终在所有游戏中都达到了六分
and so we widely believed that the
因此，我们广泛认为
problem is not polynomial cannot prove
问题不是多项式无法证明
it but we do know where it resides and
它，但我们确实知道它的位置，
within the complexity hierarchy that we
在我们的复杂性层次结构中
are familiar with
熟悉